Jiachuan Wang

☑ jiachuan.wang@u.nus.edu | 🔰 +65 85090656 | 🛍 The N.1 Institute for Health, Centre for Life Science, 28 Medical Drive, Singapore 117456 | ② Personal website | 🛅 Jiachuan Wang

SUMMARY:

I have broad interests in computational and cognitive neuroscience, with a focus on understanding the mechanisms underlying animal behavior and cognition, and an overarching goal of building models of the mind. Currently, I am pursuing a Ph.D. at the National University of Singapore, where I am developing biologically plausible models of spatial learning and associative memory. During my undergraduate studies at Zhejiang University and the University of Edinburgh, I contributed to fMRI research on human cognition and the monkey connectome.

EDUCATION:

National University of Singapore

Singapore

Ph.D. student in Medicine

Aug. 2023 – Present

Neuroscience track and Biostatistics, Bioinformatics & Epidemiology track

Zhejiang University

Hangzhou, China

B.S. in Bioinformatics

Sep. 2019 - Jun. 2023

The University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, UK

B.S. (Hons) in Biomedical Informatics

Sep. 2019 - May. 2023

GRANTS & AWARDS:

NUS Research Scholarship

Ministry of Education, Singapore and National University of Singapore

Aug. 2023 - Present

Outstanding Graduates of Zhejiang University

Zhejiang University

May. 2023

Zhejiang University Scholarship

Zhejiang University

Dec. 2022

Academic Scholarship (¥40,000)

ZJU-UoE Institute

Dec. 2022

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE:

The N.1 Institute for Health, National University of Singapore

Singapore

Graduate Researcher;

Sep. 2023 - Present

Advisors: Andrew Tan, Camilo Libedinsky, Shih-Cheng Yen

Computational models of biologically-plausible synaptic plasticity in neural networks

• Implemented spatial learning models based on spiking neuron and temporal difference error-modulated STDP rule.

Centre for Discovery Brain Sciences, The University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, UK

Rotated student; Advisor: Gediminas Lukšys

Mar. 2022 - Aug. 2023

Multi-voxel pattern analysis of human emotion and memory guided by Neurosynth (Final year project)

- Performed brain mapping on emotional dimensions and memory retrieval performance in a picture task.
- · Conducted a comparison of decoding capability using brain region information obtained from real fMRI data and a meta-analysis database.

Computational model-based analysis of spatial navigation strategies under stress and uncertainty using place and border cells

 Conducted behavioral analysis, performance assessment, and parameter estimation of a spatial navigation reinforcement learning model in the Morris Water Maze.

School of Brain Science and Brain Medicine, Zhejiang University

Hangzhou, China

Rotated student; Advisor: Zhiping Wang

Jan. 2022 - Sep. 2022 Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2020

The role of protein quality control (PQC) regulator UBE4B on the neurodevelopment of mammalian hippocampus

• Interpreted label-free quantification data and performed enrichment analysis. One publication.

Interdisciplinary Institute of Neuroscience and Technology, **Zhejiang University**

Hangzhou, China

Rotated student; Advisor: Anna Wang Roe

Apr. 2021 - Oct. 2021

Visualization software development of functional magnetic resonance data analysis results

- Developed a web-based fMRI data viewer, running on the public server of Zhejiang University.
- · Assisted in animal preparations and recorded 5 infrared neural stimulation-fMRI experiments on the amygdala of juvenile monkeys.

SERVICE:

National University of Singapore

Graduate teaching assistant

• Beginning Artificial Intelligence Through Neuroscience

Fall 2024

· LSM4213 Systems Neurobiology

Fall 2024

Edinburgh University Students' Association (EUSA)

Programme Representative (Biomedical Informatics)

2021 - 2022

ASSOCIATIONS:

ALBA Network

TALKS & POSTERS:

- Qiu, Y., Wang, S., Wang, J., Zhu, W., Cheng, Y., Aydemir, B., Gerstner, W., Sandi, C. and Luksys, G. Computational model-based analysis of spatial navigation strategies under stress and uncertainty using place, distance and border cells. PS03-27AM-195. Poster presentation delivered at the Federation of European Neuroscience Societies (FENS) Forum 2024, Vienna, Austria, June, 2024.
- Wang, S., Wang, J., Zhu, W., Cheng, Y., Aydemir, B., Qiu, Y., Gerstner, W., Sandi, C. and Luksys, G. Computational model-based analysis of spatial navigation strategies under stress and uncertainty using place, distance and border cells. Program No. 235.23. 2023 Neuroscience Meeting Planner. Poster presentation delivered at the Society for Neuroscience meeting, Washington, D.C., November, 2023.

• Wang, S., Qiu, Y., Cheng, Y., **Wang, J.**, Zhu, W., Aydemir, B., Gerstner, W., Sandi, C. and Luksys, G. Computational model-based analysis of spatial navigation strategies under stress and uncertainty using place, distance and border cells. Poster presentation delivered at the 50th Meeting of the **European Brain and Behaviour Society**, Amsterdam, Netherlands, August, 2023.

PUBLICATIONS:

- Kong, X., Shu, X., **Wang, J.**, Liu, D., Ni, Y., Zhao, W., Wang, L., Gao, Z., Chen, J., Yang, B., Guo, X. and Wang, Z. (2022) Fine-tuning of mTOR signaling by the UBE4B-KLHL22 E3 ubiquitin ligase cascade in brain development. *Development*. doi: 10.1242/dev.201286.
- Zhang, L., Ma, X., Wu, Z., Liu, J., Gu, C., Zhu, Z., **Wang, J.**, Shu, W., Li, K., Hu, J. and Lv, X. (2022) Prevalence of ground glass nodules in preschool children: a cross-sectional study. *Translational pediatrics*. doi: 10.21037/tp-22-465.

SKILLS:

• Languages: Mandarin (native), English

• **Programming Languages**: Python, R, PostgreSQL, Bash. Basics of: C/C++, Java.

• Applications: ITK-SNAP, COPASI, IGV, PyMOL, Git, LATEX